this problem has given us
a hash referenced by the local variable
numbers
we are asked to iterate over this
number's hash
using the enumerable map method
and return an array that contains each
number
divided by 2. we're going to
assign the returned array to a variable
called half numbers
and output its value
the map method that we're going to be
using in this problem
is defined in the enumerable module
you'll learn more about how this is
possible in future courses
for now all you need to know is that
this enumerable map
method is available to all hashes
another interesting part of this problem
is that
although we are iterating over a hash
we're going to return an array
you can look at the innumerable map
documentation to
read more about how this method works
let's begin to write some code
we know we want to store the returned
array in a local variable called half
numbers
so we're going to invoke the map method
on our numbers hash
and as we iterate through the hash each
key
and each value will be passed to the
block
the key will be assigned to the first
block parameter
and the value will be assigned to the
second
in this case we've called these block
parameters key and value
but we could have named them anything
the key will always be assigned to the
first block parameter
and the value will always be assigned to
the second
let's think about what we need to do
within our block
the map method performs transformation
based on the return value of its block
in this case we want that transformation
to be that we
are dividing each value by two
so we can simply return from the block
the return value of dividing value by 2.
so let's output half numbers
which is an array and see if our output
matches the expected output that we were
given
and it does
be sure to read the documentation for
any method that you're unfamiliar with
in this case if you weren't familiar
with the enumerable map
method you may be surprised to know that
it returns an array
even when we invoke it on a hash